Step right up, folks!
Ayo maju, teman-teman!
Step right up and see our hall of freaks and curiosities!
Datanglah dan lihatlah aula keanehan dan keingintahuan kami!
The Lee Twins, joined at birth by a cruel trick of God!
Si Kembar Lee, bersatu saat lahir karena tipu daya kejam Tuhan!
Careful.
Hati-hati.
And the dog-faced boy,
Dan anak laki-laki berwajah anjing itu,
more dog than boy.
lebih mirip anjing daripada anak laki-laki.
The Skeleton Man,
Manusia Kerangka,
more dead than alive.
lebih banyak yang mati daripada yang hidup.
Slorak, the Man-Ape,
Slorak, si Manusia-Kera,
more ape than man.
lebih mirip kera daripada manusia.
Come on. They're all here.
Ayo. Semuanya ada di sini.
Step right up...
Melangkahlah ke atas...
into a grotesquerie of horrors beyond your darkest imaginings.
menjadi suatu kengerian yang mengerikan yang melampaui imajinasi tergelap Anda.
Step right up.
Melangkah maju.
There you go.
Itu dia.
Keep moving.
Jalan terus.
Hello, boy.
Halo, anak laki-laki.
Come closer.
Mendekatlah.
Don't be afraid. Come closer.
Jangan takut. Mendekatlah.
Come on. Come closer.
Ayo. Mendekatlah.
Yeah. That's right.
Ya, benar sekali.
Now you see it!
Sekarang Anda melihatnya!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wah, wah, wah.
There you are.
Itu dia.
For the love of Christ.
Demi cinta Kristus.
Don't be a damn sissy, Francis.
Jangan jadi banci, Francis.
Your old man won you something.
Ayahmu memenangkan sesuatu untukmu.
Come on.
Ayo.
-Step right up. -Thank you.
-Silakan maju. -Terima kasih.
Come on.
Ayo.
God.
Tuhan.
Damn fair cleaned me out.
Sialan, adil, bersihkan aku.
Get us some water.
Ambilkan kami air.
One please.
Satu saja, tolong.
Come on now, hurry up.
Ayo, cepatlah.
It's five cents.
Harganya lima sen.
That's all I got.
Hanya itu saja yang kumiliki.
That a slingshot?
Itu ketapel?
Where's that damn slingshot?
Di mana ketapel sialan itu?
Wait! Francis! No! Come back! Wait!
Tunggu! Fransiskus! Tidak! Kembalilah! Tunggu!
Francis! Come back!
Fransiskus! Kembalilah!
What do you want?
Apa yang kamu inginkan?
Leave me alone!
Tinggalkan aku sendiri!
Hello.
Halo.
Run, come on!
Ayo lari!
Hurry.
Buru-buru.
He's getting closer!
Dia makin dekat!
Don't look back!
Jangan melihat ke belakang!
Look at the logjam.
Lihatlah kemacetan itu.
Yippee!
Hura!
Mrs. Bainbridge.
Nyonya Bainbridge.
Pleasure to see you again.
Senang bertemu Anda lagi.
I've upped Lilly's dosage of chlorpromazine,
Saya telah meningkatkan dosis klorpromazin Lilly,
but if she has another episode,
tapi jika dia mengalami episode lain,
we may want to discuss a more restrictive treatment plan.
kita mungkin ingin membahas rencana perawatan yang lebih ketat.
Where is she now?
Dimana dia sekarang?
Lilly forged quite the bond last summer with the head of our housekeeping staff.
Lilly menjalin ikatan yang erat musim panas lalu dengan kepala staf tata graha kami.
She wanted to say goodbye before she left.
Dia ingin mengucapkan selamat tinggal sebelum pergi.
Fold and tuck.
Lipat dan selipkan.
It's going to be okay, dear.
Semuanya akan baik-baik saja, sayang.
You're a bright girl. You'll figure it out.
Kamu gadis yang cerdas. Kamu pasti bisa.
Yeah, it's just...
Ya, itu hanya...
It's my fault that her dad's in jail.
Ini salahku kalau ayahnya masuk penjara.
We don't even know each other that well.
Kita bahkan tidak begitu mengenal satu sama lain.
And if I tell the truth about what I really saw, then--
Dan jika aku mengatakan kebenaran tentang apa yang benar-benar aku lihat, maka--
You'd probably wind up right back here.
Anda mungkin akan berakhir kembali di sini.
What would you do if you were me?
Apa yang akan kamu lakukan jika kamu jadi aku?
My father used to say that life is about the journey.
Ayah saya biasa berkata bahwa hidup adalah tentang perjalanan.
But I think it's more about who you take that journey with.
Namun menurutku, yang penting adalah dengan siapa Anda menjalani perjalanan itu.
And if this Ronnie means as much to you as it sounds,
Dan jika Ronnie ini berarti bagi Anda seperti kedengarannya,
you're going to find a way to make things right.
Anda akan menemukan cara untuk memperbaiki keadaan.
Somehow.
Bagaimanapun.
Listen.
Mendengarkan.
If you tell me that you've seen the impossible...
Jika Anda mengatakan kepada saya bahwa Anda telah melihat hal yang mustahil...
then I believe you.
kalau begitu aku percaya padamu.
Most people, well...
Kebanyakan orang, yah...
they only believe what they can see...
mereka hanya percaya apa yang mereka lihat...
with their own eyes.
dengan mata kepala mereka sendiri.
Easy, partner.
Tenang saja, kawan.
I come in peace.
Saya datang dengan damai.
What's the matter, not your brand?
Apa masalahnya, bukan merek Anda?
I'm more of an Embassy Golds man.
Saya lebih ke arah pendukung Embassy Golds.
Is that right? Embassy Golds.
Benarkah? Embassy Golds.
Not too popular this side of the pond.
Tidak terlalu populer di sisi kolam ini.
To think, I had you pegged as a Pall Mall man,
Kalau dipikir-pikir, aku sudah menganggapmu sebagai manusia Pall Mall,
a regular James Coburn.
James Coburn biasa.
Lee Marvin.
Lee Marvin.
Pall Malls, the commercials are Lee Marvin.
Pall Malls, iklannya adalah Lee Marvin.
Well, you do know your movie stars, Hank. Guess it comes with the territory, huh?
Wah, kamu tahu banget bintang filmmu, Hank. Kayaknya itu sudah jadi kewajiban, ya?
You know what I know, what my... my territory is?
Kau tahu apa yang kutahu, apa... wilayahku?
Liars.
Pembohong.
I can sniff 'em out a mile away.
Aku bisa mencium baunya dari jarak satu mil jauhnya.
Where were you the night of the murder, Hank?
Di mana kamu pada malam pembunuhan itu, Hank?
I told you, I was home.
Sudah kubilang, aku di rumah.
Then why do I have an eyewitness, puts you on Jackson Street at 11:30?
Lalu mengapa saya punya saksi mata, yang menempatkan Anda di Jackson Street pukul 11:30?
Yeah, a witness called it in, said she saw your picture in the papers.
Ya, ada saksi yang melaporkannya, dan mengatakan dia melihat fotomu di koran.
Put two and two together with the man
Hubungkan dua dan dua dengan pria itu
she'd seen sneaking around in the shadows that night.
dia lihat menyelinap di balik bayangan malam itu.
-She wrote a sworn statement. -Yeah, it don't make it true.
-Dia menulis pernyataan di bawah sumpah. -Ya, itu tidak menjadikannya benar.
Well, she was pretty upset.
Wah, dia cukup kesal.
So, we went out there, had a look around, and...
Jadi, kami pergi ke sana, melihat-lihat, dan...
found this at the scene.
menemukan ini di tempat kejadian.
"Thou shalt not lie," Hank.
"Jangan berbohong," kata Hank.
Do you know what they do to kiddy-killers in Shawshank?
Tahukah Anda apa yang mereka lakukan terhadap pembunuh anak-anak di Shawshank?
I didn't do nothing to those kids,
Aku tidak melakukan apa pun pada anak-anak itu,
and I wasn't nowhere near that theater.
dan saya tidak berada di dekat teater itu.
Then where were you, Hank?
Lalu di mana kamu, Hank?
And don't give me any more guff about you being at home in bed.
Dan jangan ganggu aku lagi soal kamu yang sedang di rumah dan tidur.
Don't insult my intelligence.
Jangan menghina kecerdasanku.
All right.
Baiklah.
We're gonna miss you around here, Hank.
Kami akan merindukanmu di sini, Hank.
At least we got the memories.
Setidaknya kita punya kenangannya.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. wait.
Tunggu, tunggu, tunggu, tunggu, tunggu, tunggu, tunggu, tunggu. tunggu.
I... I didn't do this! I didn't do this!
Aku... Aku tidak melakukan ini! Aku tidak melakukan ini!
Come back! Come back!
Kembalilah! Kembalilah!
Can you imagine if your dad turns out to be a psycho killer?
Dapatkah Anda bayangkan jika ayah Anda ternyata seorang pembunuh psikopat?
I mean, they must have evidence if they arrested him, right?
Maksudku, mereka pasti punya bukti kalau mereka menangkapnya, kan?
This is America. You can't just throw people in jail for nothing.
Ini Amerika. Kita tidak bisa begitu saja memenjarakan orang tanpa alasan.
Are we talking about the same country?
Apakah kita berbicara tentang negara yang sama?
She just doesn't seem like the kind of person
Dia sepertinya bukan tipe orang yang
that would've been raised by a killer.
yang pasti akan dilakukan oleh seorang pembunuh.
That's all.
Itu saja.
Hey.
Hai.
Grabbed this from the nurse's office. It should help get that off.
Ambil ini dari ruang perawat. Semoga bisa membantu menghilangkannya.
You're the last person I need help from.
Kaulah orang terakhir yang aku butuhkan bantuannya.
You're lucky I don't whoop your ass for what you did to my dad.
Beruntungnya kau, aku tidak memukulmu atas apa yang kau lakukan pada ayahku.
You just walk on out of here.
Kau tinggal pergi dari sini.
-Just go. -I'll tell them, okay?
-Pergilah. -Akan kukatakan pada mereka, oke?
What I really saw.
Apa yang sebenarnya saya lihat.
-You will? -I'll do anything to make it right.
-Kau mau? -Aku akan melakukan apa saja untuk memperbaikinya.
It happened again at the grocery store.
Itu terjadi lagi di toko kelontong.
I saw my dad.
Aku melihat ayahku.
They sent me back to Juniper Hill.
Mereka mengirim saya kembali ke Juniper Hill.
Now everyone thinks I'm still crazy or,
Sekarang semua orang mengira aku masih gila atau,
I don't know, even more crazy. So even if I tell them the truth,
Entahlah, malah lebih gila lagi. Jadi, meskipun aku mengatakan yang sebenarnya,
no one's gonna believe it.
tidak seorang pun akan mempercayainya.
People only believe what they can see for themselves.
Orang-orang hanya percaya pada apa yang dapat mereka lihat sendiri.
It won't matter what we tell them unless we can show them proof.
Tidak akan penting apa yang kita katakan pada mereka, kecuali kita bisa menunjukkan buktinya.
How are we supposed to get proof?
Bagaimana kita bisa mendapatkan buktinya?
You actually think this thing is gonna stop
Kamu benar-benar berpikir hal ini akan berhenti
and pose for pictures?
dan berpose untuk foto?
What have we got to lose? It's worth a shot.
Apa ruginya? Patut dicoba.
To prove that I'm not crazy and that your dad's not a killer.
Untuk membuktikan bahwa aku tidak gila dan ayahmu bukan pembunuh.
Okay.
Oke.
Say we try this and we actually get something.
Katakanlah kita mencoba ini dan kita benar-benar mendapatkan sesuatu.
What are we gonna do?
Apa yang akan kita lakukan?
Send it to Keene's to get developed?
Kirim ke Keene untuk dikembangkan?
We'd never get those pictures back.
Kami tidak akan pernah mendapatkan foto-foto itu kembali.
And I don't know how to develop a roll of film.
Dan saya tidak tahu bagaimana cara mengembangkan gulungan film.
-Do you? -No.
-Benarkah? -Tidak.
But there must be someone we know who can.
Namun pasti ada seseorang yang kita kenal yang bisa.
We stripped that Caddy down to the bolts.
Kami bongkar Caddy itu sampai ke bautnya.
If there was anything hidden inside, we'd have found it. It's clean.
Kalau ada yang tersembunyi di dalamnya, pasti sudah kami temukan. Bersih.
Nothing but blood stains and bullet holes.
Tidak ada apa-apa selain noda darah dan lubang peluru.
We even checked the area around the dig site.
Kami bahkan memeriksa area sekitar lokasi penggalian.
Must have dug up half an acre. Still no luck.
Pasti sudah menggali setengah hektar. Masih belum berhasil.
Of course not.
Tentu saja tidak.
What we're looking for was buried in Derry 300 years
Apa yang kami cari terkubur di Derry 300 tahun yang lalu
before the automobile was even invented.
sebelum mobil ditemukan.
But that car had to give off something for Hallorann to be able to find it.
Tetapi mobil itu harus mengeluarkan sesuatu agar Hallorann dapat menemukannya.
It's part of the 1935 cycle.
Itu bagian dari siklus 1935.
The Bradley Gang massacre.
Pembantaian Geng Bradley.
Bunch of Dillinger wannabes.
Sekelompok orang yang ingin menjadi Dillinger.
Town went crazy and shot them to hell.
Kota menjadi gila dan menembak mereka ke neraka.
Eyewitness reports at the time suggest sightings of the entity
Laporan saksi mata pada saat itu menunjukkan penampakan entitas tersebut
in one of its forms.
dalam salah satu bentuknya.
Everything we've dug up so far
Segala sesuatu yang telah kami gali sejauh ini
and we're no closer to locating the target.
dan kita belum juga menemukan targetnya.
And we're running out of time.
Dan kita kehabisan waktu.
Hallorann's psychic abilities have been proven,
Kemampuan psikis Hallorann telah terbukti,
but there's only so much he can do stuck on base pointing at maps.
tetapi tidak banyak yang dapat dilakukannya selain terjebak di pangkalan sambil menunjuk peta.
We need to get him closer to the target.
Kita perlu mendekatkannya ke target.
Right on top of it if possible.
Tepat di atasnya jika memungkinkan.
On top of it, sir?
Di atas itu semua, Tuan?
Put him in the air.
Taruh dia di udara.
Hallorann is the key to this whole operation.
Hallorann adalah kunci dari keseluruhan operasi ini.
If something should happen to him--
Jika sesuatu terjadi padanya--
We have Major Hanlon to look after him now.
Kami memiliki Mayor Hanlon untuk menjaganya sekarang.
Well, with all due respect, sir,
Baiklah, dengan segala hormat, Tuan,
how do we know Hallorann will do any better out in the field?
bagaimana kita tahu Hallorann akan tampil lebih baik di lapangan?
Maybe he just needs a little something extra to guide him.
Mungkin dia hanya butuh sesuatu tambahan untuk membimbingnya.
Something that put its mark on that thing
Sesuatu yang memberi tanda pada benda itu
a long time ago.
dahulu kala.
Ain't no way.
Tidak mungkin.
-Bullshit. Bullshit. -Ain't no way.
Omong kosong. Omong kosong. -Tidak mungkin.
There ain't no way. Ain't no way.
Tak mungkin. Tak mungkin.
You ain't never made it with Aretha Franklin.
Anda tidak pernah berhasil bersama Aretha Franklin.
Hand to God!
Tangan untuk Tuhan!
We met in Detroit. At a club.
Kami bertemu di Detroit. Di sebuah klub.
Spent the night together. Shit, she even wrote a song about me.
Menghabiskan malam bersama. Sial, dia bahkan menulis lagu tentangku.
Yeah, "Won't Be Long."
Ya, "Tidak Akan Lama."
Goddamn, man.
Sialan, bung.
Fuck!
Persetan!
I thought you were supposed to have special privileges.
Saya pikir Anda seharusnya memiliki hak istimewa khusus.
So, what?
Jadi bagaimana?
So, can't you get us a little upgrade?
Jadi, tidak bisakah Anda memberi kami sedikit peningkatan?
Hallorann. It's time.
Hallorann. Waktunya telah tiba.
We want that upgrade.
Kami menginginkan peningkatan itu.
Masters, son of a bitch. I'd love to get him
Tuan, brengsek. Aku ingin sekali menangkapnya.
and his buddies alone, let me tell you.
dan teman-temannya sendiri, izinkan saya katakan.
It's too bad, because Masters and his pals
Sangat disayangkan, karena Masters dan teman-temannya
-shipped off yesterday, so it's done. -Yeah, tell that to my right shoulder.
-dikirim kemarin, jadi sudah selesai. -Ya, sampaikan itu ke bahu kananku.
You gotta man up, Pauly.
Kau harus berani, Pauly.
-"Man up"? -Yeah.
-"Jadi pria sejati"? -Ya.
I was taking those two guys down while you were still
Aku akan menjatuhkan kedua orang itu saat kamu masih
under the bed looking for your jaw. "Man up."
di bawah tempat tidur mencari rahangmu. "Berani, dong."
I don't remember you taking anyone down.
Aku tidak ingat kamu menjatuhkan seseorang.
I remember you were getting tossed around like a baby.
Aku ingat kamu dilempar ke sana kemari seperti bayi.
I'm a lover, not a fighter.
Saya seorang pecinta, bukan petarung.
-Yeah? -Yeah.
-Hah? -Hah.
Then why are you in the military? Why'd you join?
Lalu kenapa kamu masuk militer? Kenapa kamu bergabung?
-I look so good in the uniform. -Yeah?
-Aku terlihat cantik mengenakan seragam itu. -Ya?
-No, not the hair. Not the hair. -Fuck you.
-Bukan, bukan rambutnya. Bukan rambutnya. -Persetan denganmu.
Touch that, you die. You know that.
Sentuh itu, kamu mati. Kamu tahu itu.
-Major. -Colonel.
-Mayor. -Kolonel.
Airman Hallorann, this is Major Hanlon,
Prajurit Hallorann, ini Mayor Hanlon,
Captain Russo. They'll be your crew for today's surveillance flight.
Kapten Russo. Mereka akan menjadi kru Anda untuk penerbangan pengintaian hari ini.
How they hangin', fellas?
Bagaimana kabarnya, teman-teman?
Sir, what exactly are we gonna be surveilling this afternoon?
Pak, apa sebenarnya yang akan kita awasi sore ini?
Your consoles.
Konsol Anda.
Think of Hallorann here as a human compass.
Bayangkan Hallorann sebagai kompas manusia.
You go wherever he says to.
Kamu pergi ke mana pun dia menyuruhmu.
-Sounds good. -Let's get you in the air.
-Kedengarannya bagus. -Ayo kita terbangkan kamu.
-So, Hallorann. -Yeah?
-Jadi, Hallorann. -Ya?
What's with the cigars?
Ada apa dengan cerutu?
No cigars in here.
Dilarang cerutu di sini.
Well, then what's in it?
Baiklah, lalu apa isinya?
You wouldn't understand.
Anda tidak akan mengerti.
You're-- You're gonna need to turn east.
Kamu-- Kamu harus berbelok ke timur.
East. Now!
Timur. Sekarang!
Roger that. East we go.
Dier, kita ke timur.
Why-- Why are you stopping? We have to get out of here.
Kenapa-- Kenapa kamu berhenti? Kita harus keluar dari sini.
We're okay now. Look.
Kita baik-baik saja sekarang. Lihat.
It doesn't leave the woods.
Ia tidak meninggalkan hutan.
What was that thing?
Apa benda itu?
I don't know.
Aku tidak tahu.
Stop, please.
Tolong berhenti.
Why can't it leave the woods?
Mengapa ia tidak bisa meninggalkan hutan?
Can you keep a secret?
Bisakah Anda menyimpan rahasia?
I don't know what they think they're doing out there.
Saya tidak tahu apa yang mereka pikir mereka lakukan di luar sana.
Our ceremonial grounds have always been off limits.
Tempat upacara kami selalu terlarang.
-If they want the land-- -They always want the land.
-Jika mereka menginginkan tanah-- -Mereka selalu menginginkan tanah.
Then at least give us a fair price
Kalau begitu setidaknya beri kami harga yang pantas
so that we can fix things up around the Marsh.
sehingga kami dapat memperbaiki keadaan di sekitar Marsh.
She's right. We're, what, an hour outside of Derry?
Dia benar. Kita, berapa, satu jam di luar Derry?
We might as well be on different planets.
Kita mungkin saja berada di planet yang berbeda.
The tax money they got to pave their streets.
Uang pajak yang mereka dapatkan digunakan untuk mengaspal jalan mereka.
The car they dug up?
Mobil yang mereka gali?
This isn't about airing long-standing grievances...
Ini bukan tentang mengutarakan keluhan yang sudah lama ada...
It was Al Bradley's.
Itu milik Al Bradley.
From '35.
Dari '35.
The massacre.
Pembantaian.
If you're going to represent our interests...
Jika Anda akan mewakili kepentingan kami...
We have to do something now, Auntie.
Kita harus melakukan sesuatu sekarang, Bibi.
-Before they get any closer-- -No.
-Sebelum mereka mendekat-- -Tidak.
And so do they.
Dan begitu pula mereka.
You and your friends are not to get involved.
Anda dan teman-teman Anda tidak boleh terlibat.
Not in this.
Tidak dalam hal ini.
You're needed.
Anda dibutuhkan.
Do you understand?
Apakah kamu mengerti?
This is about you doing what you were elected to do.
Ini tentang Anda melakukan apa yang Anda dipilih untuk lakukan.
If anyone has any suggestions, they should speak up now.
Jika ada yang punya saran, sebaiknya bicara sekarang.
John, something has to be done. Now.
John, sesuatu harus dilakukan. Sekarang.
I've requested to meet,
Saya sudah meminta untuk bertemu,
asking for a special liaison to the community.
meminta penghubung khusus ke masyarakat.
We've heard nothing, so what do you suggest?
Kami belum mendengar apa pun, jadi apa saran Anda?
Something stronger.
Sesuatu yang lebih kuat.
We start with a cease-and-desist letter.
Kita mulai dengan surat larangan dan penghentian.
-That's bullshit. -Give them some time to respond,
-Itu omong kosong. -Beri mereka waktu untuk merespons,
and if we still hear nothing, we file a formal complaint
dan jika kami masih tidak mendengar kabar, kami akan mengajukan pengaduan resmi
through the federal government.
melalui pemerintah federal.
You know they'll just ignore it.
Anda tahu mereka akan mengabaikannya.
You want to stop them?
Anda ingin menghentikan mereka?
I don't.
Saya tidak.
Not until I find out
Tidak sampai aku mengetahuinya
what it is they're actually doing out there.
apa yang sebenarnya mereka lakukan di luar sana.
Hey, Hallorann, you all right back there?
Hei, Hallorann, kamu baik-baik saja di sana?
Hallorann!
Aula!
The hell's he doing?
Apa yang sedang dia lakukan?
You think I know what's going on with him?
Kau pikir aku tahu apa yang terjadi padanya?
Hallorann!
Aula!
"Human compass"? Look at this fucking guy.
"Kompas manusia"? Lihat orang sialan ini.
Look like a human compass to you? He's having a goddamn fit.
Kelihatannya seperti kompas manusia, ya? Dia lagi marah-marah.
Jesus Christ.
Yesus Kristus.
Ground, this is USAF-KC135.
Darat, ini USAF-KC135.
I got a buddy at Fort Bragg, he was saying that they're doing, like,
Saya punya teman di Fort Bragg, dia bilang mereka melakukan, seperti,
mind control on goats or some shit.
pengendalian pikiran pada kambing atau semacamnya.
Is that what this is? Is this some goat shit, Lee?
Apa ini yang seperti itu? Apa ini kotoran kambing, Lee?
There appears to be something wrong with Hallorann. Unresponsive.
Sepertinya ada yang salah dengan Hallorann. Tidak responsif.
-Requesting permission to head back. -That's a negative, Major Hanlon.
-Meminta izin untuk kembali. -Itu negatif, Mayor Hanlon.
-Maintain present course. -I'm advising again. Unresponsive.
-Tetap pada jalur yang sekarang. -Saya menyarankan lagi. Tidak responsif.
Requesting permission to head back.
Meminta izin untuk kembali.
I'm advising that Airman Hallorann is unresponsive!
Saya memberi tahu bahwa Airman Hallorann tidak responsif!
Requesting permission to head back!
Meminta izin untuk kembali!
Hallorann!
Aula!
Hey! Hallorann!
Hai! Hallorann!
Who are you?
Siapa kamu?
Grandma.
Nenek.
He's coming, Dickie.
Dia datang, Dickie.
Get out of here. Now!
Keluar dari sini. Sekarang!
Hallorann! Step back, Hallorann!
Hallorann! Mundurlah, Hallorann!
-Hallorann! Hallorann! -No! No!
-Hallorann! Hallorann! -Tidak! Tidak!
-Hey! Hey! -You both in?
-Hei! Hei! -Kalian berdua ikut?
-How you holding up, soldier? -I feel fine, sir.
-Bagaimana keadaanmu, prajurit? -Saya baik-baik saja, Tuan.
So...
Jadi...
you saw it.
kamu melihatnya.
More like it saw me.
Lebih tepatnya dia melihatku.
What was it like?
Seperti apa rasanya?
Cold.
Dingin.
You did good up there today.
Kau melakukannya dengan baik hari ini.
If there's anything
Jika ada sesuatu
we can do to make your time here a little easier,
kami dapat melakukan apa saja untuk membuat waktu Anda di sini sedikit lebih mudah,
you let me know.
kamu beritahu aku.
-Now that you mention it... -That was quick.
-Sekarang setelah kau menyebutkannya... -Itu cepat sekali.
Me and my pals on base, it's kind of hard to find a place to blow off steam.
Aku dan teman-teman di pangkalan, agak sulit menemukan tempat untuk melepaskan penat.
If you can see fit to find us someplace that
Jika Anda merasa cocok untuk menemukan kami di suatu tempat yang
maybe it don't rain in on our heads, I know the boys would be grateful.
mungkin hujan tidak turun di kepala kita, aku tahu anak-anak akan berterima kasih.
Understood. I'll see what I can do.
Dimengerti. Saya akan lihat apa yang bisa saya lakukan.
Sir.
Pak.
It wasn't supposed to see us.
Seharusnya ia tidak melihat kita.
It wasn't supposed to know.
Seharusnya dia tidak tahu.
I got a feeling
Aku punya firasat
we keep on like we're doing, something bad is coming.
jika kita terus melakukan seperti ini, sesuatu yang buruk akan datang.
Maybe we oughta just let this thing be.
Mungkin sebaiknya kita biarkan saja hal ini terjadi.
Rest up.
Beristirahatlah.
Here you go, gentlemen.
Baiklah, Tuan-tuan.
The trip was supposed to be short,
Perjalanan itu seharusnya singkat,
but the launch was delayed for over three hours
tapi peluncurannya tertunda lebih dari tiga jam
after Shepard climbed into the rocket.
setelah Shepard naik ke roket.
So Shepard asked if he could go outside and pee,
Jadi Shepard bertanya apakah dia bisa keluar dan buang air kecil,
and they said no, but they had to temporarily
dan mereka bilang tidak, tapi mereka harus melakukannya untuk sementara waktu
turn off the electrical parts in his suit
matikan bagian listrik di jasnya
so he could pee in his pants without frying himself.
jadi dia bisa kencing di celana tanpa harus menggoreng dirinya sendiri.
So, you're telling me the first human
Jadi, kau memberitahuku manusia pertama
that went to space went there with pee in his pants?
that went to space went there with pee in his pants?
Yeah.
Ya.
It could have been worse.
It could have been worse.
Dude, stop!
Dude, stop!
You got it on your face.
You got it on your face.
Let me ask you this.
Let me ask you this.
Who do you think has the best ta-tas in the grade?
Who do you think has the best ta-tas in the grade?
What?
Apa?
Do they not call them ta-tas where you're from?
Do they not call them ta-tas where you're from?
-No, they do. -Well, for me, it's Delores.
-No, they do. -Well, for me, it's Delores.
Even though Marge Truman has the better face.
Even though Marge Truman has the better face.
Ronnie Grogan?
Ronnie Grogan?
What does she want with you?
What does she want with you?
-Can I what? -Develop film.
-Can I what? -Develop film.
I mean, the way you talked about that stink bomb,
I mean, the way you talked about that stink bomb,
thought maybe you knew what type of chemicals
thought maybe you knew what type of chemicals
you needed in a dark room.
you needed in a dark room.
Can't you just send it out to a lab?
Can't you just send it out to a lab?
No. Can you help us or not?
No. Can you help us or not?
Maybe, but why?
Maybe, but why?
You wouldn't believe us if we told you.
You wouldn't believe us if we told you.
Try me.
Try me.
So, what do you think?
So, what do you think?
Why did I agree to this?
Why did I agree to this?
I can't help her.
I can't help her.
Well, do you believe her?
Well, do you believe her?
I believe she believes it.
I believe she believes it.
But when she asked me, it's like my mind just went blank.
But when she asked me, it's like my mind just went blank.
-Love will do that to you. -Yeah.
-Love will do that to you. -Yeah.
-Wait, what? -Ronnie. You're sweet on her.
-Wait, what? -Ronnie. You're sweet on her.
-I know the signs. -There are no signs.
-I know the signs. -There are no signs.
Sure there are.
Sure there are.
Love can make you do some crazy things, pal.
Love can make you do some crazy things, pal.
Like climb a balcony or-- or...
Like climb a balcony or-- or...
Or write a poem on the inside of your shoe
Or write a poem on the inside of your shoe
so no one finds out about it.
so no one finds out about it.
Who writes poems on the inside of their shoes?
Who writes poems on the inside of their shoes?
Just someone.
Just someone.
Someone in love.
Someone in love.
Okay, but I'm not in love with Ronnie.
Okay, but I'm not in love with Ronnie.
Whatever you say, Romeo.
Whatever you say, Romeo.
Let me know if you need any help.
Let me know if you need any help.
You looking for anything special today?
You looking for anything special today?
Well, I don't know.
Well, I don't know.
What do you have for a nickel?
What do you have for a nickel?
-Francis Shaw. -Has it really been 50 years?
-Francis Shaw. -Has it really been 50 years?
Doesn't seem possible.
Doesn't seem possible.
No, it doesn't.
No, it doesn't.
It's the oddest thing.
It's the oddest thing.
Before I got here, I... I didn't remember you at all.
Before I got here, I... I didn't remember you at all.
-You really know how to flatter a gal. -I mean, I didn't remember any of it.
-You really know how to flatter a gal. -I mean, I didn't remember any of it.
-You. This town. -You're not the first.
-You. This town. -You're not the first.
Derry's funny that way.
Derry's funny that way.
No matter how long you spend here, the further away you get,
No matter how long you spend here, the further away you get,
the more it all just seems to fade.
the more it all just seems to fade.
Some would say it's for the best.
Some would say it's for the best.
I don't know.
I don't know.
It has its charms.
It has its charms.
What do you remember?
What do you remember?
Not much.
Not much.
My father, life on the base, but mostly I remember you.
My father, life on the base, but mostly I remember you.
It was one summer, Francis. We were 12.
It was one summer, Francis. We were 12.
I doubt you even remembered my name.
I doubt you even remembered my name.
I didn't.
I didn't.
Not until this week.
Not until this week.
You're in charge of the digs?
You're in charge of the digs?
What are you doing out there, Francis?
What are you doing out there, Francis?
Soil surveys.
Soil surveys.
We're trying to figure out where to lay pipe
We're trying to figure out where to lay pipe
to bring in water from the Kenduskeag.
to bring in water from the Kenduskeag.
And our community is concerned
And our community is concerned
that your dig will disturb sacred remains.
that your dig will disturb sacred remains.
We can't allow unmarked burial grounds to be destroyed.
Kita tidak dapat membiarkan tanah pemakaman yang tidak bertanda dihancurkan.
Then let's work together.
Kalau begitu, mari kita bekerja sama.
You can show us exactly what areas to stay away from.
Anda dapat menunjukkan kepada kami area mana saja yang harus dihindari.
I know it might not mean much coming from a man in my position,
Saya tahu hal ini mungkin tidak berarti banyak jika datang dari seorang pria di posisi saya,
but you can trust me.
tapi Anda dapat percaya pada saya.
I'd like to believe that.
Saya ingin mempercayai itu.
I will talk to the town council.
Saya akan berbicara dengan dewan kota.
No promises.
Tidak ada janji.
I'll be in touch.
Saya akan menghubungi Anda.
It's nice to see you, Rose.
Senang bertemu denganmu, Rose.
You too.
Kamu juga.
What's the matter? Why do you look so sad?
Ada apa? Kenapa kamu terlihat sedih sekali?
My dad got his redeployment orders.
Ayah saya mendapat perintah penempatannya kembali.
We leave in the morning.
Kami berangkat pagi hari.
I was gonna wait to give this back to you, but...
Aku akan menunggu untuk mengembalikannya padamu, tapi...
I think you should have it. Something to remember me by.
Kurasa kamu harus punya ini. Sesuatu untuk mengenangku.
You have to promise me something, okay?
Kau harus berjanji sesuatu padaku, oke?
Promise me you'll never forget me, this summer,
Berjanjilah padaku kau tidak akan pernah melupakanku, musim panas ini,
us being friends.
kita berteman.
Francis, you don't know this yet, but...
Francis, kamu belum tahu ini, tapi...
this place has a way of making people forget,
tempat ini punya cara untuk membuat orang lupa,
even if they don't want to.
bahkan jika mereka tidak menginginkannya.
Holy smokes! This place is the living end, man!
Astaga! Tempat ini benar-benar kiamat, Bung!
How do you even know about it?
Bagaimana kamu tahu tentang itu?
It's my friends' place. Their hangout.
Itu tempat teman-temanku. Tempat nongkrong mereka.
Or it was.
Atau memang begitu.
No way! I love these!
Nggak mungkin! Aku suka banget!
So, how do we get this picture?
Jadi, bagaimana kita mendapatkan gambar ini?
Well, I guess we could either wait for it
Baiklah, kurasa kita bisa menunggunya
to come after us again or... I don't know, somehow draw it out?
untuk mengejar kita lagi atau... entahlah, entah bagaimana mengulur waktu?
What are all the ways this thing has come after you so far?
Apa saja hal yang telah mengejarmu sejauh ini?
Matty, my dad.
Matty, ayahku.
-Ronnie's mom. -Yeah, but it's not them.
-Ibu Ronnie. -Ya, tapi bukan mereka.
It's something pretending to be them, to scare us.
Itu sesuatu yang berpura-pura menjadi mereka, untuk menakut-nakuti kita.
The right question would be, what in the hell is it?
Pertanyaan yang tepat adalah, apa-apaan ini?
-It's an orixá. -What?
-Itu orix??. -Apa?
You know, an evil spirit.
Kau tahu, roh jahat.
Well, they're not all evil, but this one sounds pretty bad.
Yah, tidak semuanya jahat, tetapi yang ini kedengarannya cukup buruk.
How do you know?
Bagaimana kamu tahu?
Well, I don't know for sure, but my tío was a babalao.
Baiklah, saya tidak tahu pasti, tapi t??o saya adalah babalao.
Back in Cuba, a Santería priest.
Kembali di Kuba, seorang Santer??seorang pendeta.
He told me whenever someone welched on him,
Dia mengatakan kepadaku setiap kali ada orang yang mengejeknya,
you know, didn't pay back money and stuff,
kamu tahu, tidak membayar kembali uang dan sebagainya,
he'd conjure this orixá and send it after them.
dia akan menyulap orix ini?? dan mengirimkannya kepada mereka.
And the really mean ones
Dan yang benar-benar jahat
always took the form of their dead ancestors.
selalu mengambil wujud leluhur mereka yang sudah meninggal.
You know, to really freak them out.
Kau tahu, untuk benar-benar membuat mereka ketakutan.
And he was able to just conjure them?
Dan dia bisa saja memunculkannya?
Yeah, but he had to go to a cemetery, light candles.
Ya, tetapi dia harus pergi ke kuburan dan menyalakan lilin.
It was a whole big thing.
Itu adalah sesuatu yang besar.
Crazy, right?
Gila, kan?
Go! Go! Go!
Ayo! Ayo! Ayo!
No! Stupid wind!
Tidak! Angin bodoh!
Rich...
Kaya...
Did he ever tell you how?
Apakah dia pernah memberitahumu caranya?
Evening, ma'am.
Malam, Bu.
-Thank you. Come on in. -Yes, ma'am.
-Terima kasih. Silakan masuk. -Baik, Bu.
Major.
Besar.
-Don't sell yourself short. -You put some Spanish saffron in this?
-Jangan meremehkan dirimu sendiri. -Kamu masukkan sedikit kunyit Spanyol ke dalamnya?
Ain't much in the way of Cajun cuisine in these parts, I'm afraid.
Saya khawatir, tidak banyak masakan Cajun di daerah ini.
Things are certainly different here,
Hal-hal tentu saja berbeda di sini,
I'll give you that.
Aku akan memberikan itu padamu.
We're getting into the swing of it, though.
Kami mulai terbiasa dengan hal itu.
Starting to feel like home.
Mulai merasa seperti di rumah.
You don't like it much down here, do you, Mrs. Hanlon?
Anda tidak begitu suka dengan suasana di sini, bukan, Nyonya Hanlon?
Oh, I like it fine.
Oh, baiklah, saya menyukainya.
You know, it's hard not to miss the things you leave behind.
Tahukah Anda, sulit untuk tidak merindukan hal-hal yang Anda tinggalkan.
We don't need to get into all that.
Kita tidak perlu membahas semua itu.
I was a history teacher.
Saya adalah seorang guru sejarah.
Colored school?
Sekolah berwarna?
There another kind down there that'd let me teach?
Ada yang lain di sana yang memperbolehkan saya mengajar?
Fair enough.
Cukup adil.
We tried to find something at a school up here,
Kami mencoba mencari sesuatu di sekolah di sini,
but all they had was clerical work. She's overqualified.
Tapi yang mereka miliki hanyalah pekerjaan administrasi. Dia terlalu berkualifikasi.
There were other things. Meetings, marches.
Ada hal-hal lain. Rapat, pawai.
-Please. -The movement.
-Silakan. -Gerakan.
The Major is worried my activism
Mayor khawatir dengan aktivisme saya
will reflect poorly on him with his colleagues.
akan memberikan kesan buruk tentang dirinya di mata rekan-rekannya.
Hamper his ascent up the military food chain.
Menghambat kenaikannya dalam rantai makanan militer.
I can see how that could be a concern, ma'am.
Saya dapat melihat bagaimana hal itu bisa menjadi suatu kekhawatiran, Bu.
It's hard enough being colored in the service.
Sudah cukup sulit untuk diwarnai dalam pelayanan.
And you got any real ambition, you gonna want
Dan jika kamu punya ambisi yang nyata, kamu akan menginginkannya
your personal life to be cleaner than your uniform.
kehidupan pribadi Anda lebih bersih dari seragam Anda.
Well, I'm not surprised y'all two flyboys stick together.
Baiklah, saya tidak heran kalian berdua, jagoan terbang, tetap bersatu.
Excuse me, I'm gonna get dessert started.
Permisi, saya mau mulai menyiapkan makanan penutup.
So, where's your son at tonight?
Jadi, di mana putramu malam ini?
Will?
Akan?
You'll meet him sometime.
Anda akan bertemu dengannya suatu saat nanti.
But he's at a friend's house now.
Tapi sekarang dia ada di rumah temannya.
This camera's boss.
Kamera ini bosnya.
Oh, man. I've never seen one of these before.
Wah, aku belum pernah lihat yang seperti ini sebelumnya.
Will.
Akan.
What's with the face?
Ada apa dengan wajahnya?
Nothing.
Tidak ada apa-apa.
Hey, Ronnie.
Hai, Ronnie.
Don't waste film.
Jangan buang-buang film.
We need every picture we can get.
Kami butuh setiap gambar yang bisa kami dapatkan.
-All right, sorry. -Look okay?
-Baiklah, maaf. -Terlihat baik-baik saja?
-We did everything like you said. -Yeah, great. A-plus.
Kami melakukan semuanya seperti yang kamu katakan. - Ya, bagus. Bagus sekali.
Okay.
Oke.
-Should we start? -Yeah, sure.
-Haruskah kita mulai? -Ya, tentu.
Why not? Come on.
Kenapa tidak? Ayo.
Hell of a meal, Major.
Makanan yang luar biasa, Mayor.
Your wife know her way around the kitchen.
Istri Anda tahu caranya di dapur.
I never told you we had a son.
Aku tidak pernah memberitahumu kalau kami punya seorang putra.
Must have heard it from someone on base.
Pasti mendengarnya dari seseorang di pangkalan.
What happened up there?
Apa yang terjadi disana?
I mean, closing your eyes
Maksudku, menutup matamu
to look for something.
untuk mencari sesuatu.
What is that?
Apa itu?
My grandmama said it's like...
Nenekku bilang seperti...
it's like seeing things without seeing things.
itu seperti melihat sesuatu tanpa melihat sesuatu.
Yeah, I know. It sounds crazy, right?
Ya, aku tahu. Kedengarannya gila, kan?
Place I grew up, everybody knew someone who knew someone that was like that.
Di tempat saya tumbuh, semua orang mengenal seseorang yang mengenal seseorang yang seperti itu.
I've just never seen it for myself.
Saya belum pernah melihatnya sendiri.
It's funny, just before,
Lucu sekali, tepat sebelum itu,
you asked me about my son, I felt something.
Anda bertanya kepada saya tentang anak saya, saya merasakan sesuatu.
Yeah, somewhere in the back of my brain.
Ya, di suatu tempat di bagian belakang otakku.
Can't describe it really, other than it's the strangest
Tidak bisa menggambarkannya dengan jelas, selain itu adalah hal yang paling aneh
goddamn thing I've ever felt in my whole life.
hal terkutuk yang pernah kurasakan sepanjang hidupku.
And I've only felt it one other time.
Dan saya hanya merasakannya satu kali lainnya.
The night I was attacked...
Malam saat aku diserang...
you were there.
kamu ada di sana.
It wasn't you holding the pipe, but I know what I felt.
Bukan kamu yang memegang pipa itu, tapi aku tahu apa yang kurasakan.
Stay out of my head. We clear?
Jangan ganggu pikiranku. Kita bereskan?
I will. I will. You don't have to worry about that.
Aku akan melakukannya. Aku akan melakukannya. Kamu tidak perlu khawatir tentang itu.
What is that supposed to mean?
Apa maksudnya itu?
I've seen what men think about when they're facing death.
I've seen what men think about when they're facing death.
They think about their families. They think about their regrets.
They think about their families. They think about their regrets.
But you?
But you?
Gun to your head, finger on the trigger.
Gun to your head, finger on the trigger.
You were analyzing.
You were analyzing.
You were just...
You were just...
collecting information.
collecting information.
It's like the part of your brain that's supposed to be afraid,
It's like the part of your brain that's supposed to be afraid,
it's not even there.
it's not even there.
So, you are not
So, you are not
the kind of fella I'm likely to fuck with, Major.
the kind of fella I'm likely to fuck with, Major.
But you saved my life up in that bird.
But you saved my life up in that bird.
So I sure wouldn't mind having you with me in them trenches.
So I sure wouldn't mind having you with me in them trenches.
All right.
All right.
Who's ready for some dessert?
Who's ready for some dessert?
Mud cake's just about done.
Mud cake's just about done.
-I would love some mud cake. -All right.
-I would love some mud cake. -All right.
Come on, Lee.
Come on, Lee.
Rich, you're just repeating yourself.
Rich, you're just repeating yourself.
What is that? What are you saying?
What is that? What are you saying?
The Santa Maria?
The Santa Maria?
The prayer for the dead?
The prayer for the dead?
Now we wait.
Now we wait.
Feels like we should be facing away from each other to see out, right?
Feels like we should be facing away from each other to see out, right?
Yeah, that's what my uncle said to do.
Yeah, that's what my uncle said to do.
Yeah. Yeah, good idea.
Yeah. Yeah, good idea.
Sorry.
Maaf.
Gotta take a whiz.
Gotta take a whiz.
No. Wait, wait, I thought you said
No. Wait, wait, I thought you said
we couldn't leave the circle until it was done.
we couldn't leave the circle until it was done.
No, you can. You just have to come back quickly.
No, you can. You just have to come back quickly.
My cousin told me.
My cousin told me.
You said your uncle did it.
You said your uncle did it.
Well, yeah, but I mostly heard about it from my cousin, so--
Well, yeah, but I mostly heard about it from my cousin, so--
You didn't hear it from him?
You didn't hear it from him?
Well, not the whole thing.
Well, not the whole thing.
-This is so messed up. -Okay, we're leaving.
-This is so messed up. -Okay, we're leaving.
Hold on, guys, he was just trying to help.
Hold on, guys, he was just trying to help.
Making up all this mumbo jumbo?
Making up all this mumbo jumbo?
Come on. Monsters, ghosts, it's all mumbo jumbo.
Come on. Monsters, ghosts, it's all mumbo jumbo.
So, you still don't believe me?
So, you still don't believe me?
You think it's just my imagination?
You think it's just my imagination?
I... I believe you believe it.
I... I believe you believe it.
I'm sorry, okay? I... I didn't...
I'm sorry, okay? I... I didn't...
-Ro-- Ron! -Wait, Ronnie!
-Ro-- Ron! -Wait, Ronnie!
It's just hard making friends.
It's just hard making friends.
-You know? -I know, man. I know.
-You know? -I know, man. I know.
You okay?
You okay?
I don't want to talk about it.
I don't want to talk about it.
Come on, Rich! We gotta catch up!
Come on, Rich! We gotta catch up!
Are you seeing this?
Are you seeing this?
Something's wrong, I think.
Something's wrong, I think.
Hey, Ron, slow down. Ron, wait up.
Hey, Ron, slow down. Ron, wait up.
Whoa!
Whoa!
What's happening?
What's happening?
Go, go, go!
Go, go, go!
We're almost there!
We're almost there!
Tío?
T??o?
No, tío!
No, t??o!
What's happening?
What's happening?
This can't be real. This can't be real.
This can't be real. This can't be real.
I got it! I got it!
I got it! I got it!
Oranges and lemons Say the bells of St. Clement's
Oranges and lemons Say the bells of St. Clement's
Rich! Get the camera!
Rich! Get the camera!
I see it!
I see it!
I got it! I got it!
I got it! I got it!
Flashlight.
Flashlight.
Oh, shit!
Oh, shit!
Oh, shit! Whoa!
Oh, shit! Whoa!
-Rich? -Will, get the camera!
-Rich? -Will, get the camera!
Oh my God, what the hell was that?
Oh my God, what the hell was that?
Where's Will? Guys, guys! hey, guys, stop!
Where's Will? Guys, guys! hey, guys, stop!
He was just right behind me.
He was just right behind me.
-Come on! -Hurry!
-Come on! -Hurry!
-Come on! Oh my God! -Hurry, get out of there!
-Come on! Oh my God! -Hurry, get out of there!
Come on!
Come on!
-I should have believed you. -You're damn right!
-I should have believed you. -You're damn right!
Do you need help?
Do you need help?
Shit, I think I just broke both my femurs.
Sial, kurasa kedua tulang pahaku baru saja patah.
Okay, so first we're going to set up three trays
Oke, pertama kita akan menyiapkan tiga baki
and a water bath.
dan mandi air.
-Fill one tray with developer. -Smells like Fizz-A-Lot.
-Isi satu baki dengan pengembang. -Baunya seperti Fizz-A-Lot.
-Can you drink these? -No.
-Bisakah kamu meminumnya? -Tidak.
One with mixer and the other with stop bath.
Satu dengan mixer dan yang lainnya dengan stop bath.
Rich, don't touch that.
Rich, jangan sentuh itu.
Red light.
Lampu merah.
Timer.
Pengatur waktu.
And now we wait.
Dan sekarang kita menunggu.
Holy shit.
Gila.
I took that.
Aku ambil itu.
Guys, come on.
Teman-teman, ayo.
Here.
Di Sini.
Teddy!
Boneka Teddy!
We did it.
Kita berhasil.
-We actually did it. -Oh my God.
-Kami benar-benar melakukannya. -Ya Tuhan.
Come on, next one. Let's go. Wait, this way, right?
Ayo, selanjutnya. Ayo. Tunggu, ke sini, ya?
-No, other way. -Okay. Here.
-Tidak, jalan lain. -Baiklah. Di sini.
Susie!
Susie!
Yes! Oh my gosh.
Ya ampun.
Yes.
Ya.
-Ronnie. -I'm coming.
-Ronnie. -Aku datang.
It's the picture I took in the crypt.
Itu gambar yang saya ambil di ruang bawah tanah.
What is that?
Apa itu?
It's a clown.
Itu badut.